



#### **Nicolas Vargas**

<u>nikolas210680@gmail.com</u> 431-373-3022 Calgary, AB https://nickvargas.dev/

### Full Stack Developer

## Expert in operations, focused on developing his tech career. No project or task is impossible.

Critical thinker, enthusiastic learner, and passionate professional with over 15 years of experience working in big teams, specializing in full-stack development and data analysis. Committed and efficient, adept at prioritizing tasks to meet deadlines while embracing challenges. Capable of working independently to achieve goals.

#### **Technical and Essential Skills:**

- JavaScript
- HTML & CSS
- React JS
- Node JS
- Express JS

- Rest API
- Git
- MongoDB
- Firebase & Firestore
- Agile Methodologies

- Project Management
- Software Development
- Client Support

## **Current Projects for our Ecosystem:**

## Park n' Bike Project:

In collaboration with a team of 3, created an application that simplifies Calgary's cycle-path network to enable riders the ability to take a leisurely bike ride with ease on set out pathways. Developed using MERN stack, using Auth0 for authentication.

Technologies Used: JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Express JS, REST API, Git, MongoDB, Mapbox, Canva

## StriveOpp Scholarship Project:

In collaboration with a team of two, created a web application for StriveOpp company, oriented to scholarships and government grant seekers, providing them with matching pattern tools to find the scholarship that best suits their interest based on experience, professional background, and studies.

Technologies Used: JavaScript, Vite React, NodeJS, Firebase, Jira, Bootstrap, Cheerio, Firebase Auth, Firestore Database.

https://github.com/nvargas210680/StriveOpp

## **Professional Experience:**

# Operations Supervisor for Robinson Supply, Heating Division, Winnipeg, Canada February 2020 to October 2022

- Conducted training needs analysis to optimize team members' skills.
- Maintained professional relationships with customers, contractors, and vendors.
- Provided administrative, counseling, and coaching support.
- Oversaw operations and implemented strategies to reduce PO's variances by 90%.
- Ensured company goals and Key Performance Indicators were met, implementing SOPs and operational controls for inventory and customer returns, and resolving logistic events, inventory discrepancies, and billing issues promptly and accurately.

# Project Coordinator for Iris Construction Management, Winnipeg, Canada. January 2019 – January 2020

- Coordinated and managed multiple projects, handling requirements and communication with stakeholders.
- Created comprehensive project documentation and summary reports for company management.
- Engaged with clients to define project requirements, scope, and objectives.
- Offered technical support to the project manager, devising action plans with stakeholders to overcome challenges.
- Ensured projects adhered to frameworks and maintained up-to-date documentation.
- Supervised employees and contractors to ensure project success and quality.

# **Academic Coordinator/English teacher** Antiguo Instituto Electronico de Idiomas February 2015 — November 2018 Bogota-Colombia

- Developed pedagogical materials and trained teachers in English language instruction methods.
- Implemented educational processes and procedures to enhance the learning experience.
- Conducted audits of company learning plans and educational materials while devising strategies to boost sales and attract new customers.

# **Supervisor Teleperformance SA** – Virgin Mobile-Assurance Wireless Campaign February 2011-December 2014

- Managed teams of over 20 customer service representatives in bilingual English/Spanish data entry roles
- Led a specialized retention line for key customers across five states in the US.
- Entered data from diverse sources into systems with a focus on first call resolution.

• Coached and developed representatives conducted hiring and training and implemented action plans to achieve key performance indicators like adherence, absenteeism, AHT, QA, and Customer Care.

#### **Volunteer:**

YYC Tech Talent Tour April 28<sup>th</sup>, 2023 InceptionU – event coordinator – Feb -Jul 2023

## **Education and Training:**

# Full Stack Developer learner at Inception

Onsite, full time 6 months program Feb 2023 - Jul 2023

## Foundations: Data, Data everywhere Coursera

Online certificate Nov 2022-Jan 2023

## Ask questions to Make Data-Driven Decisions Coursera

Online certificate Nov 2022 – 2023

## Prepare Data for Exploration Coursera

Online certificate Nov 2022 – Jan 2023

# **Distribution Manager Development Course**

Texas A&M University Dec 2021 – Dec 2021

# First Aid Training Center Winnipeg Manitoba

**CPR Certification Oct 2021** 

# **Administrative and Management Certificate**

Teleperformance SA Bogota-Colombia Jan 2014 – Nov 2014

# Professional Diploma on Teaching English as Mother Language

Antiguo Electronico de Idiomas Jun 2009 – Jun 2010

# Languages

Fluency in English and Spanish Basic French